# M. ESAT OZEN

Full Stack Software Developer Greater Boston Area Massachusetts (203) 278 6572 ozenesat@gmail.com https://ozenesat.github.io/ https://github.com/ozenesat https://linkedin.com/in/ozenesat

#### SKILLS

JavaScript
React.js
Node.js
Next.js
Express
Mongoose
Mango DB
Ruby on Rails
SQL

PostgreSQL Git/GitHub Phabricator jQuery AJAX JSON Handlebars HTML5 CSS

#### **WORK STATUS**

Bootstrap

Linux/Ubuntu

Green Card Holder

# EDUCATION

# General Assembly

Software Engineer

*Immersive* 

Middle East Technical University (METU) Bachelor of Science

**Mathematics** 

Abstract Algebra Combinatorics

Complex Calculus

Cryptography

**Discrete Mathematics** 

Introduction to C

Mathematical Analysis

Number Theory

#### LEADERSHIP

President of the Student Council @ METU

#### **SUMMARY**

With mathematics degree and startup experience able to master new skills quickly. Enjoy breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking, while transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Experienced in diverse work areas in 3 different countries as a highly adaptive, fast learning world citizen.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Rapic.io - Remote — Front-End Developer

May 2020 - Present

- Integrate the OAuth functionality into React application with back-end server.
- Working with a global dev team over Phabricator with scrum methodology.
- Design, implement and test the React application from scratch with Next.js.

# General Assembly - Boston, MA — Software Engineer Immersive February 2020 – May 2020

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- As a capstone project developed full-stack SPA, <u>Photo Collector</u>, using the technologies React, Node, Express, MongoDB, with OAuth and 3 party APIs.
- Completed 4 full-stack web applications in 4-day sprints each, independently & collaboratively and practiced Agile methodology.
- Learned and critically applied 15+ new languages, libraries, databases, and other technologies. Utilized Git and GitHub for version control.
- Greatly exceeded curriculum expectations by completing ~100 extra hours of additional material.
- Built quality RESTful APIs and integrated data from third-party APIs.

# Ace It Education - Boston, MA — Web Developer

May 2019 - February 2020

- Created and maintained the two websites of the company with WordPress.
- Organized tech events in cooperation with people of diverse backgrounds.
- Managed social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

### The Fix - Farmington, CT — Stores Manager

May 2018 – May 2019

- Managed the finances and personnel of the company's branches at four different locations. Scheduled the employee shifts and acted as Human Resources.
- Efficiently managed ~\$1 million yearly budget and increased profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services for customer needs.

# Zaman Media Group - Ankara, Turkey — Correspondent

May 2014 - April 2016

- Worked with editors and senior correspondents as a team to cover all of the latest political news from the Capitol. Reported judicial news from the courts.
- Acted as the assistant to the Executive Officer in Ankara headquarters of the media outlet.